Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm 5976 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Correspondence 1958-1961 (Reel 11)
  - 0834. June-December 1961. 95 pages., 8 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Walter Reuther's efforts to replace George Meany as American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations president; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations report on civil rights by A. Philip Randolph; Negro apprentices; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organization Civil Rights Committee activities; proposed merger of the Great Northern, Northern Pacific, and Burlington Railroads; George Meany's statement to the Special Subcommittee on Labor of the House Committee on Education and Labor; discrimination on the Canadian National Railway; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights publications; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations leaders rebuke A. Philip Randolph for creating gap between organized labor and the Negro community; President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights resolution.
- Correspondence 1962-1969 (Reel 12)
  - 0001. January-June 1962. 106 pages., 1 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities and minutes of meetings; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People criticism of Kennedy administration's civil rights position; state fair employment practice laws; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Economic and Legislative Conference; discrimination by an International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers union local; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations policy regarding use of segregated facilities; George Meany's testimony regarding the Federal Equal Employment Opportunity Bill; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Staff Conference on Civil Rights; porter grievances.
  - 0107. July-December 1962. 80 pages., 2 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights compliance cases; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; antidiscrimination provisions in major contracts; take-over of operations of Pullman sleeping car service by the Pennsylvania Railroad; report of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board; National Association for the Advancement of Colored Peoples charges of racial discrimination by the International Ladies Garment Workers Union; George Meany's address to the Negro American Labor Council; union programs for fair employment practices; wage scale for porters on the SOO line; American Federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations progress in integration of local unions; legislative obstruction by the rules Committee in the United States House of Representatives.
  - 0187. 1963. 120 pages., 3 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: National Railroad Adjustment Board decision in favor of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities and minutes of meetings; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights compliance cases; death of A.L. Totten; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations policy on civil rights; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations progress in integration of local unions; search of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members by Pullman Company special agents; porter grievances; porter sleeping accommodations; operation of extra employees; Pullman disciplinary action and hearing against porter; civil rights developments involving building and construction trade.
  - 0307. January-May 1964. 143 pages., 4 (Reel 12)
    Porter grievances; injury claims by porters; passenger complaints against porters; meeting of American Federation of Labor-congress of Industrial Organizations General Board; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; porter time claims; Advisory Committee on Union Plans for Fair Practices.
  - 0450. June-September 1964. 137 pages., 5 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: Porter grievances; passenger complaints against porters; National Mediation Board investigation of representation dispute affecting employees of the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad; Pullman disciplinary action and hearing against porter.
  - 0587. October-December 1964. 89 pages., 6 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: injury claims; passenger complaints against porters; porter grievances; report on the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations and the Negro; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Conference for Santa Fe and Union Pacific chair car attendants.
  - 0676. 1965-1967. 208 pages., 7 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: Mediation agreement between the railroads represented by the National Railway Labor Conference and the Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committees and their employees represented by the Employees' National Conference Committee; employment stabilization agreement; basic month; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman agreement effective January 1, 1953, revised July 1, 1965; porters' vacation agreement; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize dining car employees of the Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad; death of Milton Webster; passenger complaints against porters; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations resolutions on civil rights; Railroad Retirement Board Informational Conferences; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman union deductions agreement; minority housing problems; Illinois Committee for Fair Housing Law; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Union Pacific Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; discontinuation of passenger trains; credit legislation; 1967 civil rights bills.
  - 0884. 1968-1969. 180 pages., 8 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: Social, racial, and educational problems in Chicago; porter seniority rosters; discontinuation of passenger trains; Illinois fair housing legislation; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations voter registration campaign; testimonial dinner in honor of A. Philip Randolph; claims for porter separation allowances from Pullman; dues collection; Labor Conference on Civil Rights; results of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters elections; passenger complaints against porters; retirement of A. Philip Randolph as Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters president; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company agreement; Jerome Miles versus Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Pullman Company.
- Correspondence (Undated) and Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention Materials 1938-1975 (Reel 13)
  - 0001. Undated Items (1). 99 pages., 1 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: Pullman porters' grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; list of Chicago busboys and attendants; union representation for porters on the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad Company agreement; A. Philip Randolph's speech at the First Baptist Church of Memphis, Tennessee; alleged raid by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters on jurisdiction of Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters divisions; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials.
  - 0100. Undated Items (2). 143 pages., 2 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; union representation election for porters on the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad; mediation of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman dispute; state public utility laws; creation of Illinois Fair Employment Practices Commission; in charge service; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership lists.
  - 0243. Undated Items (3). 104 pages., 3 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters volunteer organization committees; lists of men contacted by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organization committees; delinquent members; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters local division officers.
  - 0347. Undated Items, 1940-1947. 275 pages., 4 (Reel 13)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; discrimination against Negroes by the railroads; Pullman activities to aid the war effort; union representation election for Pullman yard and shop employees; Pullman Company records donated to Newberry Library in Chicago; American Federation of Labor support for Negro workers; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; report on Negro pioneers in the Chicago labor movement; proceedings of the First National Convention of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary.
  - 0622. Notebook: 1938 Convention. 140 pages., 5 (Reel 13)
    Major Topic: Report of proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Fifth National Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on September 19-24, 1938.
  - 0762. Notebook: 1940 Convention. 276 pages., 6 (Reel 13)
    Major Topic: Report on the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in New York City on September 15-20, 1940.
- Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention Materials 1938-1975 (Reel 14)
  - 0001. Notebook: 1942 Convention. 80 pages., 1 (Reel 14)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Saint Louis, Missouri, on September 13-18, 1942.
  - 0081. Notebook: 1944 Convention. 113 pages., 2 (Reel 14)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Cleveland, Ohio on September 17-22, 1944.
  - 0194. Notebook: 1946 Convention. 144 pages., 3 (Reel 14)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois, on September 16-20, 1946.
  - 0338. Notebook: 1948 Convention. 117 pages., 4 (Reel 14)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Detroit, Michigan on September 12-17, 1948
  - 0455. Notebook: 1950 Convention. 162 pages., 5 (Reel 14)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in New York City on September 10-16, 1950
  - 0617. Notebook: 1953 Convention. 120 pages., 6 (Reel 14)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Los Angeles, California on October 4-9, 1953.
  - 0737. Notebook: 1956 Convention. 141 pages., 7 (Reel 14)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Saint Louis, Missouri, on September 10-14, 1956
- Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention Materials 1938-1975 (Reel 15)
  - 0001. Notebook: 1959 Convention. 155 pages., 1 (Reel 15)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on September 6-11, 1959
  - 0156. Notebook: 1962 Convention. 147 pages., 2 (Reel 15)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Montreal, Canada, on September 9-14, 1962
  - 0303. Notebook: 1965 Convention. 154 pages., 3 (Reel 15)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on September 12-17, 1965
  - 0457. Notebook: 1968 Convention. 63 pages., 4 (Reel 15)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in New Orleans, Louisiana on September 2-4, 1968
  - 0520. Notebook: 1971 Convention. 103 pages., 5 (Reel 15)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on September 13-15, 1971
  - 0623. Notebook: 1975 Convention. 82 pages., 6 (Reel 15)
    Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on August 25-27, 1975.
- International Executive Board 1948-1955 (Reel 16)
  - 0001. International Executive Board Minutes (June 3-4, 1948). 23 pages., 1 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Detroit, Michigan; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters finances; rules on assignment of runs to districts, temporary discontinuance of an assignment, overtime pay rates, and pay when used on layover or relief days; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman vacation agreement.
  - 0024. International Executive Board Minutes (September 19, 1948, Post-Convention). 51 pages., 2 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; resolution to provide protection for international officers after retirement; procedures for press releases; railroad passes for porters, preparatory time; porter sleeping accommodations; report on storeroom nonclerical employees.
  - 0075. International Executive Board. 1948 [Correspondence]. 50 pages., 3 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters finances; arrangements for International Executive Board meetings.
  - 0126. International Executive Board Minutes (April 18-19, 1949). 15 pages., 4 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in New Orleans, Louisiana; request for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial support for the Americans for Democratic Action; memorandum of understanding regarding rules on overtime pay rates and pay when used on layover or relief days; report on storeroom nonclerical employees.
  - 0140. International Executive Board Minutes (December 5-7, 1949). 41 pages., 5 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman vacation agreement; memorandum of understanding regarding rules on overtime pay rates and pay when used on layover or relief days; conference between Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Internal Revenue Service officials regarding income tax charged on tips; special presentation on education for the Negro; request for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial assistance for the National Farm Labor Union.
  - 0181. International Executive Board. 1949 (Presentations/Retirement Plan). 48 pages., 6 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Requests for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial assistance for Bethune-Cookman College and the National Farm Labor Union; special presentation on Negro education; analysis of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters pension retirement plan.
  - 0229. International Executive Board Minutes (September 8-9, 1950, Pre-Convention). 51 pages., 7 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Abolition of Pullman porter quarters; sign-out rule; minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in New York City; report of Budget Committee; report of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board.
  - 0280. International Executive Board Minutes (September 15, 1950, Post-Convention). 13 pages., 8 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in New York City; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial statements.
  - 0293. International Executive Board Minutes (May 14-16, 1951). 26 pages., 9 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Request for increase in salary of officers of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report of Budget Committee; proposed change in rule dealing with hearings for Pullman rules violations; proposed Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters pension plan.
  - 0319. International Executive Board Minutes (December 3-5, 1951). 21 pages., 10 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; proposed Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters pension plan; report of Budget Committee.
  - 0340. International Executive Board Minutes (May 5-7 1952). 65 pages., 11 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board Meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report regarding selection of site for the 1953 convention; report of Finance Committee.
  - 0405. International Executive Board Minutes (December 1-3, 1952). 19 pages., 12 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report of the Finance Committee.
  - 0424. International Executive Board Minutes (Correspondence, 1952). 43 pages., 13 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Selection of site for the 1953 convention; A. Philip Randolph and Norman Thomas's plans to visit to Japan; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meetings; reorganization of the Negro Labor Committee.
  - 0467. International Executive Board Minutes (Financial Reports), 1948-1952. 77 pages., 14 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Financial reports on the status of dues-paying members in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters divisions; annual tax payments received at International office; breakdown of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters expenses; statements of receipts and disbursements.
  - 0586. Meeting of the International Executive Board (September 1953). 14 pages., 15 (Reel 16)
    Major Topic: Report of the Finance Committee.
  - 0600. International Executive Board Minutes (October 2 and 10, 1953). 7 pages., 16 (Reel 16)
    Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Los Angeles, California.
  - 0607. Report of the International Executive Board to International Convention (October 1953). 122 pages., 17 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Report of the International Executive Board to the Los Angeles convention; membership status of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters divisions; resolutions adopted at the Los Angeles convention; pensions for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters leaders.
  - 0729. International Executive Board Meeting (May 3-6, 1954). 39 pages., 18 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Agenda and minutes of International Executive Board meeting; report of Finance Committee.
  - 0768. Supplementary Board Minutes (Meeting of May 3-6, 1954). 74 pages., 19 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; hearing on petition for reinstatement of Claude E. Grooms as Second Vice President, Chicago Division.
  - 0842. International Executive Board Minutes (December 6-8, 1954). 13 pages., 20 (Reel 16)
    Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.
  - 0855. International Executive Board Meeting (December 6-9, 1954). 47 pages., 21 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Changes in Pullman Company practice of classifying and handling parked railroad cars as station duty; operation of extra employees; request for increase in pensions for retired porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; agenda and minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; porter sleeping accommodations.
  - 0902. International Executive Board Minutes (May 16-18, 1955). 12 pages., 22 (Reel 16)
  - 0914. International Executive Board Meeting (May 16-18, 1955). 49 pages., 23 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Death of Jack Mills; minutes and agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report of the Finance Committee.
  - 0963. International Executive Board Minutes (November 27-28, 1955). 12 pages., 24 (Reel 16)
  - 0975. International Executive Board Meeting (November 27-28, 1955). 30 pages., 25 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report on reallocation of runs.
- International Executive Board 1956-1964 (Reel 17)
  - 0001. International Executive Board Minutes (May 7-9, 1956). 43 pages., 1 (Reel 17)
  - 0044. International Executive Board Minutes (Pre-Convention Meeting, Post-Convention Meeting, Special Meeting - September 6-14, 1956). 44 pages., 2 (Reel 17)
    Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meetings held in Saint Louis, Missouri.
  - 0088. Meeting of International Executive Board (September 1956). 32 pages., 3 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Agenda and minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of Finance Committee; reorganization of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; International Executive Board report for 1953-1956.
  - 0120. 1956 Convention Expenses - 2nd Triennial (1956). 7 pages., 4 (Reel 17)
    Major Topic: Receipts and expenditures of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters 1956 convention.
  - 0127. International Executive Board Minutes (May 6-8, 1957). 18 pages., 5 (Reel 17)
  - 0145. International Executive Board Meeting (May 1957). 43 pages., 6 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of the Finance Committee; vacation pay; Milton Webster's objections to election of A.R. Blanchette of Canada to International Executive Board.
  - 0188. International Executive Board Minutes (December 16-18, 1957). 33 pages., 7 (Reel 17)
  - 0221. Meeting of International Executive Board (December 16-18, 1957). 40 pages., 8 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Vacation pay for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters office employees; report of the Finance Committee; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; request for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial assistance for the United Negro College Fund; agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting.
  - 0261. International Executive Board Minutes (June 2-4, 1958). 33 pages., 9 (Reel 17)
  - 0294. Meeting of the International Executive Board (June 2-4, 1958). 28 pages., 10 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of the Finance Committee.
  - 0322. International Executive Board Minutes (December 10-11, 1958). 17 pages., 11 (Reel 17)
  - 0339. International Executive Board Minutes (December 8-11, 1958). 86 pages., 12 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; recommendations by international officers of measures to bring down Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters operating expenses; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters finances
  - 0425. Executive Board Correspondence (1958). 76 pages., 13 (Reel 17)